Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Page 1

Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Curriculum Vitae

Email: bgonzale@andrew.cmu.edu — Personal Website: brandon-joel-gonzalez.github.io

Career Objectives

Interested in electronics engineering, from systems-level design to device fabrication. Pursuing a doctorate in electrical and computer engineering, with a long-term goal of teaching and research at a university. Love of learning and helping guide others to their fullest potential.

Education

Carnegie Mellon University – College of Engineering (CIT)

- ❖ Ph.D Student in *Electrical and Computer Engineering* − August 2021 Present
 - > Research Advisor: Dr. L. Richard Carley
 - > Research Interests: rapid prototyping of computer systems, device fabrication, RF systems engineering

University of Pennsylvania – School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

- ❖ M.S.E. in *Robotics* − May 2021
- ♦ B.S.E. in *Computer Science*, minor in *Mathematics* December 2019 Cum Laude

Teaching Experience

Semesters as head TA denoted with * and semesters online denoted with ^.

- ♦ CMU 18-540/745: *Rapid Prototyping of Computer Systems* Spring 2023
 - ➤ Capstone project course exploring the development of an F1TENTH autonomous vehicle testing suite, partnered with Honda's 99P Labs
- ❖ CMU − 18-429/729: *Board-Level RF Systems for IoT* − Fall 2022*
 - > Experimental laboratory course exploring RF engineering concepts, including transmission lines, antenna design, SDR, MIMO, and beamforming
- ♦ UPenn ESE450/451: *ESE Senior Design* Fall 2019, Spring 2020^, Fall 2020*^, Spring 2021*^
 - > Two-part senior capstone project series for students in the Electrical and Systems Engineering department and related majors
- ♦ UPenn ESE350/519: Embedded Systems Lab Fall 2020[^], Spring 2021^{*^}
 - ➤ Advanced laboratory course covering the foundations and design of embedded systems platforms, across both hardware and software levels
- ❖ UPenn ESE190/M&TSI: Introduction to Hardware/Software Lab Spring 2019, Summer 2021*^
 - > Introductory laboratory course exploring the Arduino platform, primarily for students without engineering background
- ❖ UPenn CIS371/501: Computer Architecture Fall 2019, Spring 2020^
 - > Advanced systems course exploring design and optimization techniques in modern computer architecture, with labs in Verilog
- ♦ UPenn CIS380/548/CIT595: *Operating Systems* Fall 2019, Spring 2020*^, Summer 2020*^
 - ➤ Advanced systems course exploring design and implementation of operating systems, primarily Unix-based, in the C programming language
- ♦ UPenn CIS240/CIT593: *Introduction to Computer Systems* Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Summer 2019[^]
 - ➤ Introductory systems course covering topics from CMOS logic gates to architecture design to operating systems programming

Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Page 2

Research Experience

- ❖ Semiconductor Device Fabrication
 - ➤ Research part of 18-469/669 (Special Topics in Integrated Systems Technology) at CMU in Spring 2023
 - > Designing an open-source lab on CMU's campus, capable of fabricating CMOS transistors from silicon using a custom-built maskless photolithography stepper
 - ➤ Goal is to fabricate a functional transistor with 10um gate width by May 2023, then hoping to expand the capabilities of the lab to entire integrated circuits
 - ➤ Planning to use the lab for a new course in Fall 2023 that will allow students to fabricate their own ICs on-campus, as well as to continue the improvement of the lab's machines and process development
 - ➤ Links to the lab's <u>Github</u>, where resources and updates are provided
- ❖ On-Chip Interferometer
 - > Research part of Prof. Rick Carley's research group, starting in February 2023
 - > Developing an RFIC to measure ferromagnetic resonance using a novel on-chip solution, removing the necessity of a VNA-FMR
 - > Using a transmission line differential pair to detect the presence of nanoparticles as an amplitude-modulated signal, which is then amplified and downconverted to be processed off-chip
 - > Working on simulating and refining the transmission line design using Ansys Electronics Desktop software
 - > RFIC taped out in May 2023 using TSMC 28nm PDK and June 2023 using Skywater 130nm PDK
 - > Planning to test and evaluate chips in Fall 2023 and publish results
- ❖ MIT Lincoln Lab
 - Summer 2023 research intern working on RF systems design and analysis for communication systems
 - > Internship completed as part of employer sponsorship via GEM Fellowship
 - > Planning to publish experimental results in technical paper after internship

Brandon Joel Gonzalez - Page 3

Activities and Interests

- ♦ UPenn SEAS Orientation Peer Adviser for Class of 2022 (CIS) and Class of 2023 (CMPE)
- Head of Hardware team for UPenn <u>PennApps</u> hackathon from Spring 2019 to Spring 2021, organized with <u>Major League Hacking</u> (MLH)
- ❖ 2022-24 CMU Robotics Club Graduate Student Officer
- 2022-23 Officer and 2023-24 President of the <u>Eta Kappa Nu (HKN), Sigma Chapter at Carnegie Mellon University</u>

Awards and Recognitions

- * Recipient of the 2017 Penn Undergraduate Research Mentoring (PURM) Grant
- * Recipient of the 2018 Penn Engineering Exceptional Service Award
- Recipient of the 2019 <u>Littlejohn Scholars Summer Research Grant</u>
- ❖ 2019-20 J.P. Eckert Fellow
- ❖ 2020 inductee of the <u>CIS TA Hall of Fame</u>
- Recipient of the <u>Summer 2020 TA Award for Excellence in Student Support with Distinction</u>
- ❖ 2021 ESE Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Fellow
- ❖ Honorable Mention for the <u>2021 Penn Engineering Outstanding Teaching Award</u>
- Carnegie Institute of Technology Dean's Fellow
- ❖ 2022 inductee of the Eta Kappa Nu (HKN), Sigma Chapter at Carnegie Mellon University
- Selected to participate in the <u>2022 NextProf Pathfinder</u> workshop hosted by UMich and UCSD
- Completed the <u>Future Faculty Program</u> in Fall 2022 (Eberly Center for Teaching Excellence and Educational Innovation, Carnegie Mellon University)
- * Recipient of the <u>GEM Fellowship</u>, with a sponsorship by <u>MIT Lincoln Lab</u> for Summer 2023